<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Platelet</string>

    <string name="AboutApplication">Getting proper medical treatment in Bangladesh, is quiet tough.
        Moreover, having an ambulance or a bag blood of a particular type is  same as the first one . To  make things easier,
        we,  Zianur Rahman Joy and Nazmul Hasan, , are trying to make an android app that can decrease human sufferings.
        This project is being done under the guidance of Prof. Dr. MD. Ali Hossain sir. This app is called "Platelet ".
        In  this app one can have doctors appointment in "Appointment" section. Request for blood or donate blood under the "Blood" section.
        "Telemedicine" section will allow users to have doctors far apart. "Ambulance" section will allow them to request for an ambulance.
        Bangladesh is an underprivileged country.
        Ensuring medical services will allow us to acquire the goals of Sustainable Development Goals (SDG). </string>


    <string-array name="placeName">
        <item>Select Place</item>
        <item>Dhaka</item>
        <item>Barishal</item>
        <item>Rajshahi</item>
        <item>Sylhet</item>
        <item>Khulna</item>
        <item>Jassore</item>
        <item>Jhalokathi</item>
        <item>Bagura</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="placeNameH">
        <item>Barishal</item>
        <item>Jhalokathi</item>
        <item>Dhaka</item>
        <item>Rajshahi</item>
        <item>Sylhet</item>
        <item>Khulna</item>
        <item>Jassore</item>
        <item>Bagura</item>

    </string-array>


    <string-array name="tipsNameString">
        <item>Avoid sugar and sugary products</item>
        <item>Avoid extra salt</item>
        <item>Avoid junk foods</item>
        <item>Keep yourself neat and clean</item>
        <item>Maintain a healthy weight</item>
        <item>Consuming healthy food and beverages</item>
        <item>Move more and sit less throughout the day</item>
        <item>Get adequate sleep</item>
        <item>Consider eating more protein</item>
        <item>Eat seasonal fruits more</item>
        <item>Avoid tech neck</item>
        <item>Optimise your TV time</item>
        <item>Check your blood pressure regularly</item>
        <item>Cover your mouth when coughing or sneezing</item>
        <item>Prevent mosquito bites</item>
        <item>Take antibiotics only as prescribed</item>
        <item>Prepare your food correctly</item>
        <item> Have regular checkups</item>

    </string-array>


    <string name="Avoidsugarandsugaryproducts"> Eating too much added sugar can
have many negative health effects.An excess of sweetened foods and beverages can
lead to weight gain, blood sugar problems and an increased risk of heart disease,
among other dangerous conditions.For these reasons, added sugar should be kept to
 a minimum whenever possible, which is easy when you follow a healthy diet based
on whole foods.If you cut added sugar from your diet,before you know it, your sugar
 habit will be a thing of the past.</string>

    <string name="Avoidextrasalt">Salt is an essential ingredient in our cooking.
Fruits, cooked meats or vegetables and even sweets, it improves the taste of almost
everything we add it to.Salt is the primary source of sodium and increased
consumption of sodium is associated with hypertension and increased risk of heart disease and stroke.
For adults, WHO recommends that adults consume less than 5 g
(just under a teaspoon) of salt per day. </string>

    <string name="Avoidjunkfoods">Junk food is used to describe food and drinks low in nutrients
(e.g. vitamins, minerals and fibre) and high in kilojoules, saturated fat, added sugar and/or
added salt. They are also known as discretionary choices.Why is junk food bad?
Eating junk food on a regular basis can lead to an increased risk of obesity and chronic
diseases like cardiovascular disease, type 2 diabetes, non-alcoholic fatty liver disease
and some cancers.Try to Avoid them as much as possible.  </string>

    <string name="Keepyourselfneatandclean">Practicing good personal hygiene is important
for helping keep the body healthy and clean.Good personal hygiene involves keeping all parts
 of the external body clean and healthy. It is important for maintaining both physical and
 mental health.In people with poor personal hygiene, the body provides an ideal environment
for germs to grow, leaving it vulnerable to infection.On a social level, people may avoid a
 person with poor personal hygiene, which may result in isolation and loneliness. </string>

    <string name="Maintainahealthyweight">Reaching and maintaining a healthy weight is
important for overall health and can help you prevent and control many diseases and
conditions. If you are overweight or obese, you are at higher risk of developing serious
health problems, including heart disease, high blood pressure, type 2 diabetes, gallstones,
breathing problems, and certain cancers. That is why maintaining a healthy weight is so
important: It helps you lower your risk for developing these problems, helps you feel good
about yourself, and gives you more energy to enjoy life.  </string>

    <string name="Consuminghealthyfoodandbeverages">Eating and drinking healthier makes a
big difference to your body.Many people believe eating healthily is about dieting or eating less.
In fact, it’s simply a case of eating more of what your body needs and less of what it
doesn’t – what we call a balanced diet. That doesn’t have to mean boring or tasteless
food though – and you can still snack on healthier alternatives, such as fruit, raw
vegetables, rice cakes and fat-free yogurts. </string>

    <string name="Movemoreandsitlessthroughouttheday">Working out in a gym or
 playing a sport is great, but being active is about so much more than that. Think of
it as how you can use your muscles more in your everyday life. If you drive to work,
sit at a desk all day and use all the conveniences of modern life, you probably need
to move more.Making the time to be active with our busy lives can be challenging, but
start with 10 minutes and try to build up to at least half an hour of activity a day </string>

    <string name="Getadequatesleep">Sleep is an essential function1 that allows your body and mind to recharge,
leaving you refreshed and alert when you wake up. Healthy sleep also helps the body remain
healthy and stave off diseases. Without enough sleep, the brain cannot function properly.
This can impair your abilities2 to concentrate, think clearly, and process memories.Most
adults require between seven and nine hours3 of nightly sleep. Children and teenagers need
substantially more sleep, particularly if they are younger than five years of age. </string>

    <string name="Considereatingmoreprotein">The health effects of fat and carbs are controversial.
However, almost everyone agrees that protein is important.Most people eat enough protein to prevent
deficiency, but some individuals would do better with a much higher protein intake.Numerous studies
 suggest that a high-protein diet has major benefits for weight loss and metabolic health.If you
need to lose weight, improve your metabolic health, or gain muscle mass and strength, make sure you’re
 eating enough protein.</string>

    <string name="Eatseasonalfruitsmore">Seasonal fruits have higher nutritional value because they are
fresher and consumed closer to the harvesting period. Usually, antioxidants like folate, Vitamin C,
and carotenes rapidly decline when stored for a longer period of time.Also, grocers buy out-of-season
produce that has been preserved in wax, irradiated, and gassed to extend their shelf life.
Always consume fruits as per their season because they are much more healthy and preservative-free. </string>

    <string name="Avoidtechneck">When you’re working on a computer or looking down at your phone,
the muscles in the back of the neck have to contract to hold your head up. The more you look down,
the more the muscles have to work to keep your head up.A better way to sit is with the chair reclining
 25-30 degrees with a good lumbar support to prevent slouching. In this position, the discs in the back,
as well as the neck, are subjected to much lower forces than in an upright position, and the muscles in
the back of the neck no longer have to contract to hold your head up. </string>

    <string name="OptimiseyourTVtime">Next time you’re sitting down to enjoy your favourite show, take the opportunity to do
some stretching – it’ll help relieve muscle tightness, and help keep you flexible and pain-free. Try using
resistance bands, which are a cheap and compact way to maximise your limbering up time. </string>

    <string name="Checkyourbloodpressureregularly">Hypertension, or high blood pressure, is called
a “silent killer”. This is because many people who have hypertension may not be aware of the problem as
it may not have any symptoms. If left uncontrolled, hypertension can lead to heart, brain, kidney and other
diseases. Have your blood pressure checked regularly by a health worker so you know your numbers. If your
blood pressure is high, get the advice of a health worker. This is vital in the prevention and control of
hypertension. </string>

    <string name="Coveryourmouthwhencoughingorsneezing">Diseases such as influenza, pneumonia and
tuberculosis are transmitted through the air. When an infected person coughs or sneezes, infectious
agents may be passed on to others through airborne droplets. When you feel a cough or sneeze coming on,
make sure you have covered your mouth with a face mask or use a tissue then dispose it carefully. If
you do not have a tissue close by when you cough or sneeze, cover your mouth as much as possible with
the crook (or the inside) of your elbow. </string>

    <string name="Preventmosquitobites">Mosquitoes are one of the deadliest animals in the world.
Diseases like dengue, chikungunya, malaria and lymphatic filariasis are transmitted by mosquitoes.
You can take simple measures to protect yourself and your loved ones
against mosquito-borne diseases. If you’re traveling to an area with known mosquito-borne diseases,
consult a physician for a vaccine to prevent diseases such as Japanese encephalitis and yellow fever
or if you need to take antimalarial medicines. Wear light-coloured, long-sleeved shirts and pants and
use insect repellent. At home, use window and door screens, use bed nets and clean your surroundings
weekly to destroy mosquito breeding sites. </string>

    <string name="Takeantibioticsonlyasprescribed">Antibiotic resistance is one of the biggest public
health threats in our generation. When antibiotics lose their power, bacterial infections become harder
to treat, leading to higher medical costs, prolonged hospital stays, and increased mortality. Antibiotics
are losing their power because of misuse and overuse in humans and animals. Make sure you only take
antibiotics if prescribed by a qualified health professional. And once prescribed, complete the treatment
days as instructed. Never share antibiotics. </string>

    <string name="Prepareyourfoodcorrectly">Unsafe food containing harmful bacteria, viruses, parasites
or chemical substances, causes more than 200 diseases – ranging from diarrhoea to cancers. When buying
food at the market or store, check the labels or the actual produce to ensure it is safe to eat. If you
are preparing food, make sure you follow the Five Keys to Safer Food: (1) keep clean; (2) separate raw
and cooked; (3) cook thoroughly; (4) keep food at safe temperatures; and (5) use safe water and raw materials. </string>

    <string name="Haveregularcheckups">Regular check-ups can help find health problems before they start.
Health professionals can help find and diagnose health issues early, when your chances for treatment and
cure are better. Go to your nearest health facility to check out the the health services, screenings and
treatment that are accessible to you. </string>




    <string-array name="status">
        <item>Select Status</item>
        <item>Ready to donate</item>
        <item>Can not donate now</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="dept">
        <item>Select Dept</item>
        <item>Medicine</item>
        <item>Surgery</item>
        <item>Dentist</item>
        <item>Pediatric</item>
        <item>Cardiology</item>
        <item>Respiratory</item>
        <item>Neurologist</item>
        <item>Oncology</item>
        <item>Urology</item>
        <item>Psychiatrist</item>
        <item>Hematology</item>
        <item>other</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="deptAppointment">
        <item>Medicine</item>
        <item>Surgery</item>
        <item>Dentist</item>
        <item>Pediatric</item>
        <item>Cardiology</item>
        <item>Respiratory</item>
        <item>Neurologist</item>
        <item>Oncology</item>
        <item>Urology</item>
        <item>Psychiatrist</item>
        <item>Hematology</item>
        <item>other</item>

    </string-array>


    <string-array name="bloodType">
        <item>Select Blood Type</item>
        <item>A+</item>
        <item>A-</item>
        <item>B+</item>
        <item>B-</item>
        <item>O+</item>
        <item>O-</item>
        <item>AB+</item>
        <item>AB-</item>

    </string-array>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

</resources>